Guide to the Stanford University, Office of Technology Licensing, Records SC0729
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Office of Technology Licensing, records
1996-2010
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Wiesendanger, Hans U. D.
SC0729
50 Linear Feet (28 boxes)
Includes the report "Technology Based Companies Founded by Members of the Stanford University Community" and Wiesendanger's "History and Operation of the Office of Technology Licensing Stanford University," 1996.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
First series includes the report "Technology Based Companies Founded by Members of the Stanford University Community" and Wiesendanger's "History and Operation of the Office of Technology Licensing Stanford University," 1996. Later series include shadow boxes (framed patented items, each labeled with docket number and inventors).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Hans U. D. Wiesendanger, 2003; Academic transfer, 2015, 2016.
Technology -- Management.; Wiesendanger, Hans U. D.; Stanford University. Office of Technology Licensing; Wiesendanger, Hans U. D.; Wiesendanger, Hans U. D.
- Records - Patent Files
  - Patent files (Box 1)
- Additional Records - Patent Files, ARCH-2016-037
  - Digitized files, 1999-2010
  - Files
    - S05-062: Technique to retrieve phase and magnitude (Digonnet/Ozcan/Kino), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - S05-035: SFBF: Fast photonic bandgap fiber mode (Digonnet et al), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - S05-035: Patent file (Diggonet), 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - S05-035: PCT Application, PCT/US05-32229 (Litton), 2005-09-09 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - S04-159: Patent, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - S04-159: PCT, PCT/US05/017069, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - S04-148: Simulation of the effects of the core... (Digonnet et al), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - S04-148: Patent, 11/23,879, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - S04-159: Retrieval of the impulse response... (Ozcan et al), 2004 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - S03-360: Patent, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - S03-360: Patent, 10/996,166, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - S03-247: Cylinder-Assisted maker-fringe tech (Diggonet, Ozcan, Kino), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - S03-360: Post processing method (Digonnet et al), 2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - S03-240: PCT, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - S03-240: Japanese Patent (Litton), 2006 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - S03-242: Method for pulse shape design... (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - S02-236: Er-doped superflourescent... (Park, et al), 2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - S03-240: Patent papers (10/938,755), 2006 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - S03-240: CIP patent application, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - S03-240: Malaysian patent, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - S03-240: Chinese patent (STANF.135VCN), 2006 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - S03-240, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - S02-236: Patent (Litton), 2006 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - S02-236: Japanese patent (2004-541654), 2006 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - S02-236: Europe, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - S02-070: Foreign filing (Litton), 2006 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - S02-034 (10/616,693), 2006 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - S01-192: Europe, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - S01-192: Norwegian, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - S00-128: China (008198942), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - S00-128: China (2005100002351.7), 2007 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - S00-128: Canadian, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - S00-128: Japanese, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - S99-185: Norwegian, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - S99-185: Canada, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - S99-185: Japanese Patent (565693/2001), 2002 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - S98-113: Canadian, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - S98-007: Patent Canada, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - S06-280: Patent file, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - S07-047: Brag-fiber fiber-optic gyroscope (Digonnet, Michel), 2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - S07-157: Slow light for sensing: an invention disclosure (Fan, et al), 2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - S07-325: Optical and opto-mechanical devices (Solgaard, et al), 2007 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - S09-099: Fiber Bragg grating sensors used in slow light mode for ultra-high sensitivity sensing (Digonnet, et al), 2009 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - S09-144: Optomechanical fiber gyroscope (Digonnet, et al), 2009 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - 09-412: Improvements to optical acoustic sensor (Kilic, et al), 2009 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - S10-346: Optimization of Slow-light fiber Bragg grating sensors (Diggonet, et al), 2010 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - S06-258: Optical filtering using photonic-band (Diggonet etal.), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - S06-258: PROV Application (60/833108), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - S06-280: Polarization controller for air-core (Digonnet et al.), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - S05-397: Patent file (Northrop), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - S06-255: US PROV Application (60/837891), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - S06-255: US Provisional (60/817514), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - S05-397: Air-core photonic bandgap (Dangui et al.), 2005 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - S06-165: Asymetric Fabry-Perot Resonances (Digonnet etal.), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - S06-165: US Prov application (60/707714), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - S05-245: US Patent application (11/522802), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - S05-245: Silicon-nanocrystal silica microsphere thermooptical switches (Tewary, et al), 2005 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - S06-255: Reduction of thermal drift in fiber op (Digonnet et al.), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - S05-125: Optical image processing... (Ozcan et al.), 2005 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - S05-125: PCT (PCT/US06/012136), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - S05-125: US Patent, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - S05-135: High sensitivity acoustic sensor (Kilic, et al), 2005 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - S05-135: US Patent (11/414506), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - S05-069: A new optical coherence tomography (Digonnet etal.), 2005 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - S05-069: PCT (PCT/US06/009677), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - S05-125: US Patent, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - S05-069: US Patent (Litton 11/384170), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - S05-062: PCT (PCT/US06/009675), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - S05-062: US Patent, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - S05-062: PCT Application (PCT/US06/01994), 2006 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Additional Records - Shadow Boxes, Accession ARCH-2017-091
  Scope and Contents
  Shadow boxes include patented items, each labeled with docket number and inventors.
  - "Brainstorm" (S93-054); Elizabeth Tancred, Gary Coppa, SUMMIT, undated (Box 1)
  - "Computer Workstation Ergonomics CD-ROM" (S97-217); Lawrence Gibbs and Geoffrey Cox, undated (Box 2)
  - "GENSCAN: Identification of Genes in Human Genomic Sequences" (S97-072); Chris Burge, undated (Box 3)
  - "SUTECH"(S97-241); Stanford Office of Technology Licensing, undated (Box 4)
  - "HIV PCR Analysis Directs Drug Use" (S92-053); Drs. Michael Kozal and Thomas Merigan, undated (Box 5)
  - "Diet Coach - MULTIFIT" (S91-013); Dr. Robert F. DeBusk and colleagues at the Cardiac Rehabilitation Program, undated (Box 6)
  - "Arginine. Its Use as a Novel Anti-Atherogenic Agent" (S93-027); John Cooke, Victor Dzau, and Gary Gibbons, undated (Box 7)
  - "High Performance Optical Fiber Amplifiers", undated (Box 8)
  - "Secure Remote Password Authentication" (S97-006); Thomas Wu, undated (Box 9)
  - "FM Sounds" (S71-017); John Chowning, undated (Box 10)
  - "Human Biology for Middle Schools Project" (S91-007); Craig Heller, Mary Kiely, and M. Rowe, undated (Box 11)
  - "Portable Motor Symptoms Assessment Device" (S95-144); Kelvin O. Lim, undated (Box 12)
  - "MINOS" (S81-035); Bruce A. Murtagh Michael A. Saunders, undated (Box 13)
  - "Mass-produced Ordered Arrays of Active Substances" (S93-097); Patrick Brown, Tidhar Dari Shalon, undated (Box 14)
  - "Parallel Array Oligonucleotide Synthesizer Apparatus and Method for Polymer Synthesis Using Arrays" (S93-076); Dr. Thomas Brennan, undated (Box 15)
  - "Monolithic Semiconductor Switching Device (IGBT)" (S76-047); Dr. James Plummer, undated (Box 16)
  - Fiber Polarization Controller FPC-1, undated (Box 17)
  - "Agrin Monoclonal Antibodies" (S94-047); Richard H. Scheller, undated (Box 18)
  - "In-line Multichannel Microcentrifuge" (S97-116); Andre Marziali, undated (Box 19)
  - "Non-thermal Electrically Induced Closure of the Blood Vessels" (S04-115, S02-314, S02-038, S01-144, S99-049, S98-200); Daniel V. Palanker and Alexander Vankov, undated (Box 20)
  - Direct Multiplex Gene (S00-045); Ron Davis, Paul Hardenbol, Viktor Stole, Tom Willis, undated (Box 21)
  - "Non-invasive Rhythm Monitor" (S06-125); Uday N. Kumar, Joseph A. Knight, Kit Yee Au-Yeung, John W. White, undated (Box 22)
  - "Detection, Enumeration, Purification of Antigen-Specific T Cells [MHC tetramer]" (S94-140); John D. Altman, Mark M. Davis, and Michael McHeyzer-Williams, undated (Box 23)
  - "Proposal for Dense Storage of Digital Information: A Combination of the STM and the AFM" (S88-119); Calvin F. Quate Robert C. Barrett, undated (Box 24)
  - "Use of NAC for AIDS" (S99-188); Wulf Droge, Leonard A. Herzenberg and Leonore A. Herzenberg, undated (Box 25)